The Israelis are not like anybody else.
They killed a guy in a hotel room in
Dubai and then after they killed him,
they were somehow able to lock the door
from the inside of the hotel room.
>> There was like 26 people that the Dubai
CCTV footage picked up,
>> right?
>> Weren't the cameras Israeli made?
>> I got a tour of the whole facility and
the cameras were German.
>> What facility?
>> There's an underground.
Let's move into the MSAD a little bit.
>> You've talked about in interviews that
the Israelis are ranked critical threat
for counter intelligence
a little bit about our relationship with
them, but something that I'm really
interested in is the MSAD operationally
because I think again correct me if I'm
wrong, but it seems like you'd be
hardressed to argue with the fact that
they are really, really good,
>> best in the world.
So yeah, I guess broad question like
what has been your experience while at
the agency talking to other case
officers, working with the Israelis?
What stands out? My experience is
universally negative.
Universally negative.
I've never had a positive encounter with
Mossad. I have never met a CIA officer
who has had a positive encounter with
MSAD because the MSAD doesn't give two
shits what you think or what you are
trying to focus on in your job. They
care only about Israel. And if that
means shoving their fists up your ass or
trying to recruit you or telling you to
go [__] yourself while they try to
recruit, you know, the guy sitting next
to you or the guy in the defense
contractor's office, they don't care
what you think of them
because for them it's an issue of
survival. They they have nowhere to go
if they if they don't survive. The thing
is, you know, the Israelis, this was
covered in the Washington Post um uh
just a couple days after the 12-day war
started. And what the Israelis did is
that they have a lot of Farsy speaking
Jews in Israel. These are Iranians who
are Jewish and who immigrated to Israel
and a lot of them work from Wasad and
Shinbet.
And what the Israelis did was they got
the cell phone numbers of literally
every uh Iranian nuclear scientist. And
they had these Israeli Jews, I'm sorry,
these Iranian Jews call on their cell
phones, call the scientists and say,
"Listen, you're going to die tomorrow,
right? We're going to kill you tomorrow.
You have no hope. You're going to die.
Just ex accept it. Or you can defect to
us right now."
And they're like, "Ah, [__] you." and
they hang up the phone. Then they call
the wives and say, "Listen, we're going
to kill your husband tomorrow. So tell
them this is his only chance. He's going
to die tomorrow." And what they ended up
doing is just taking out the entire the
entire block of apartment buildings.
They killed 14 nuclear scientists. That
devastates the entire program
and um
and uh and family members as well. They
wiped out entire families. And now
they're gathering intelligence on the
next generation of Israeli scientists
and they're going to start killing them.
The the US would never have a policy
like that. We'll try to do, you know,
some pin prick thing or or, you know, do
it in person, but never just, you know,
kill. They killed 300 people in in um
southern Lebanon when they went after
Hassan Astrala, the former head of uh
Hezbala. Just blew up the entire
complex.
It decapitated Hezbala.
It was also a war crime.
I mean to be fair, the MSAD does do the
close-in stuff, too.
>> Yeah, they do.
>> Um like the like the Michelle one in
Jordan. And then what about that one uh
in Dubai? Do you remember that?
>> Classic. You know, we studied that for a
long time.
>> They killed a guy
in a hotel room in Dubai and then after
they killed him, they were somehow able
to lock the door from the inside of the
hotel room.
And we tried like magnets and different
ways. We couldn't figure out how they
did it.
>> Like a latched door.
>> It was they did the latch and the this
one and the guys in there dead and the
hotel couldn't even get it open. Yeah.
They ended up sending somebody in from
the balcony. How do they do that?
Very impressive.
Wasn't there also something? Okay, first
of all, the Israelis never officially
claimed responsibility for that.
But there was um there was like 26
people that
the Dub the Dubai CCTV footage picked
up.
>> Right.
>> And
>> Right. And and in Dubai they have the
most CCTV coverage in the world. More
than the Chinese,
>> but none of them were picked up.
>> No.
>> And number one, people speculate
disguises. But I also I don't know if
this is true, but weren't the cameras
Israeli made? Oh, I wouldn't be
surprised. When I was in Dubai, I got a
tour of the whole facility and the
cameras were German. What facility?
>> There's an underground.
[Music]
They have this very sophisticated.
Maybe we should clip that.
>> Oh, are you sure? I'd like to keep it
in.
>> Okay. Okay. I'm going to be serious.
There's an underground facility
that the government of Dubai has
that completely created by Seammens, the
big German company. It's like walking
into an IMAX theater, but instead of one
fivetory
uh screen, it's five stories of TV
monitors. So, you have hundreds of TV
monitors that cover every inch of Dubai.
every inch. So, we're watching these.
They gave us a tour. We're watching
these and we see um a taxi driver
looking at his phone while he's driving
and he crashes into a telephone pole and
they were like, "Uh, there's a taxi
accident at the intersection of this and
that and the taxi driver's rattled and
he gets out of the out of the cab and
he's trying to gain his, you know,
composure and somebody runs up to him
and we're watching all this on the
screen. somebody runs up to him and then
they call, you know, I think it's 115 is
their version of of 911. And um well,
the ambulance is already on the way
because we we watched it happen in real
time. So the operator is like, yes, yes,
the ambulance is on the way. The whole
country is covered. Now, you can't do
that in a country like the United
States, but you can do it in other
places and then you can intercept what's
happening in those other places. So, um,
to come back to the MSAD,
>> I told this for for people that listen
to the I had a historian, Rick Rick
Spence. He's a Oh, you know Rick? Sure.
>> Um, so for people that heard me tell the
story on that podcast, sorry about that,
but I want to get John's take on it and
you'll hear why.
>> So, um, there was a
this was a a documentary that was that
came out of Israel. So, it was all on
the up and up. And there was a MSAD
officer that told a story about um they
recruited an asset who let's say he was
like some sort of you know goat herder
or something in I believe let's I think
it was Syria and so they recruit the guy
and eventually the Palestinians come to
the guy and they wanted to recruit him
because his he was in close proximity to
the Israeli border.
>> Sure.
>> Um again I don't know if it was Syria
but whatever let's just say there was.
So the Palestinians come to him and then
he goes and tells uh the MSAD and
they're like, "Hey, I got approached by
these guys. They want to know about some
either border setup or movement of the
IDF." And what the MSAD said is, "Okay,
give them the information because let's
just assume what you can see they can
see and it's all out there. Build a
relationship. Give them the
information." Gives it to him.
>> So then they come back to him and they
say, "Okay, we want you to find a spot
in the border wall for us to cross into
Israel."
>> Oh boy. So he goes to the MSAD and he
tells him this and they say, "Okay,
let's let's go find a spot in the border
wall together and then when they come
through there'll be a warm welcome
waiting for him." So they pick a spot,
he goes and tells the Palestinians and
they say, "Okay, great. Thanks." The
night before the operation, they tell
him, they say, "Oh yeah, and by the way,
as an insurance policy, you're coming
with us."
>> Oh [__] Yeah.
>> So he tells this and they said, "Well,
if you if you say no, they'll get
spooked and they'll either you'll blow
your cover or they'll kill you."
>> Mhm.
>> So go with them and when you cross the
border, hit the deck and we have ways to
make sure that you don't get shot. And
essentially that was all [__] And
the way that the MSAD officer described
it was sacrificing a a pawn off the
chessboard. And so
I don't say that to illustrate the fact
that oh my god the MSAD is so bad. Like
intelligence is is a dirty game. I think
we're all well aware of that. But the
point what I got from that is
>> why the hell would they be saying this?
Number one to to speak to the
ruthlessness of MSAD. Sure. The
mystique. I think that that is
beneficial to an intelligence agency.
But
>> you're a Palestinian.
>> That's what I'm saying. Why would you
want to work with any agency?
>> Volunteer. Yeah.
>> Do they burn assets like that? Oh, I'm
sure that they do. I'm sure that they
do. But I'll tell you, no no no other no
other intelligence service would would
send somebody send a recruited asset to
his death like that. That doesn't make
any sense. But the Israelis are not like
anybody else.
They're not. It's just another
Palestinian
to them.
>> So, what's an example operationally like
that that you can think of when you're
like, the Israelis are different? When I
was the first time I went on Pierce
Morgan, I debated a former director of
the Mossad
and the guy just couldn't stop chuckling
all through the I mean it was
ridiculous.
I said things like the Israeli spy on
the United States.
Oh no, no, not since Jonathan Pard. And
I said, 'Well, Jonathan Pard was caught
in 1985, and you were spying on the
United States in 1998,
you know, or 2004.
No comment. It's like, what? What is
that? We would never We're not permitted
to spy on the Israelis. We're not
permitted. The potential for blowback is
is outrageous. Can you imagine if we
spied on the Israelis and got caught?
Every member of Congress would be
demanding the CIA director's head.
>> Do you think that we really don't spy on
the Israelis?
>> That was verboten when I was there.
>> I was surprised to hear you say that in
that interview because I figured it's
this gentleman's game, so to speak.
>> With most other places post 911, you
know, we develop the five eyes and we
don't spy on each other in the five
eyes. Uh the five eyes being US, UK,
Canada, Australia, New Zealand. You
know, we literally sit next to each
other in each other's headquarters. I
remember when George Tennant ordered us
to open the files, he said, and he meant
literally open the files. And so, we've
had this five eyes relationship ever
since. And of course, we have very, very
close relationships with other
countries. Not a ton, but a lot. But the
Israelis are special. Yeah. We do not
spy on the Israelis.
>> What's up, guys? Thank you so much for
taking the time to watch the interview.
If you got anything out of this video at
all, please like the video, leave me a
comment, tell me what you thought of the
video, uh, tell me who you'd like to see
on the show. I really appreciate the
support. It goes a long way on these
platforms, as you guys know. Most
importantly, I have some excellent
interviews coming up in the future that
I'm really, really excited about. So,
please subscribe to the channel so you
don't miss any of them. But that's it.
Thank you for your support.